Preliminary Inventory of the David Nelson Rowe papers
Hoover Institution Archives
David Nelson Rowe papers
1861-1982
78064
Hoover Institution Archives
143 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 oversize folder (64.9 linear feet)
Correspondence, speeches and writings, notes, reports, printed matter, photographs, slides, phonotapes, microfilm, maps, postcards, and memorabilia relating to Chinese history and foreign relations, Asian area studies, Japanese World War II propaganda, application of the People's Republic of China for admission to the United Nations, and communism in Asia.
Rowe, David Nelson, 1905-1985
Access
Collection is open for research.
Collection is stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1978, with increments received in 1981 and 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction in China (United States and China) miscellaneous records, Hoover Institution Archives
Walter H. Judd papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Alfred Kohlberg papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Marvin Liebman papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Ernest Batson Price papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Nym Wales papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Karl August Wittfogel papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1905 October 21 Born in Nanking (Nanjing), China to American missionaries of the Methodist Episcopal Church
1927 AB in political science, Princeton University
1930 AM in history, University of Southern California
1935 PhD in history, University of Chicago
1935-1937 Completed postdoctoral study at Harvard University in Chinese and Japanese language and Chinese history
1937-1938 Attended College of Chinese Studies, Peking (Beijing), China as a Rockefeller Foundation fellow
1938-1943 Lecturer in Far Eastern affairs, Princeton University
1941-1942 Special assistant to director, Branch of Research and Analysis, Office of Strategic Services Special assistant to U.S. ambassador, Chungking (Chongqing), China
1943 Author, China's Military Potential and the Enforcement of Peace, Yale Institute of International Studies
1945 Author, China Among the Powers, Harcourt Author, Collective Security in the Pacific, Institute of Pacific Relations
1945-1950 Assistant professor of international relations, Yale University
1950-1974 Professor of political science, Yale University
1951 Consultant to Stanford Research Institute
1954 Editor, China: An Area Manual, Johns Hopkins Press
1954-1955 Editor (with W. Kendall), China: A Handbook for Psywar Operators, three volumes, U.S. Operations Research
1956 Author, Recent Acquisitions of Chinese Diplomatic Archives, Academica Sinica
1958-1960 Director of graduate studies in international relations, Yale University
1959 Author, Modern China: A Brief History, Van Nostrand
1960 Editor, Index to Ch'ing Tai Ch'ou Pan I Wu Shih Mo, Shoe String
1964 Colonel, U.S. Army Reserve
1965 Editor (with Sofia S.F. Yen), Index to Su-lien Yin-Mou Wen-cheng, Shoe String
1965-1974 Director of graduate studies in international relations, Yale University
1968 Editor, New Nations, Shoe String
1969 Author, The New Diplomacy: International Technical Cooperation Projects of the Republic of China in African Countries, National Council of Scholars
1975 Author, Informal Diplomatic Relations: The Case of Japan and the Republic of China, Shoe String
1979 Author, U.S. China Policy Today, University of Professors for Academic Order
1980 Author, The Carter China Policy
1982 Author, Ally Betrayed: The Republic of China, Western Goals
1985 June 3 Died, Sun City, Arizona
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection relates to Chinese history and foreign relations, Asian area studies, Japanese World War II propaganda, the application of the People's Republic of China for admission to the United Nations, and communism in Asia. It is comprised of correspondence, speeches and writings, notes, reports, printed matter, photographs, slides, sound recordings, microfilm, maps, posters, and postcards.
Of particular note in the collection are Japanese propaganda posters, flyers, and other visual materials depicting scenes from the Second Sino-Japanese War, likely collected by Rowe during his trips to the region and used as research materials for his writings on Japanese propaganda in North China and the development of psychological warfare strategies.
Pamphlets, monographs, and newsletters relating to communism in Asia and diplomatic relations between the United States and Asia are included in the papers and are supplemented by Rowe's correspondence with others involved in anti-communist organizations in the United States, most notably Marvin Liebman and Alfred Kohlberg.
Research materials relating to the Chinese agriculture development and technical assistance missions in Africa and Latin America from 1965 to 1971 are in the collection in the form of reports, photographs, pamphlets, and maps.
No arrangement was performed by archives staff and original folder titles are used when provided.
United Nations--China.; Asia--Study and teaching.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--Foreign relations.; China--History--20th century.; Communism--Asia.; Phonotapes.; Propaganda, Japanese.; Sino-Japanese Conflict, 1937-1945.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.
- Japanese propaganda in China, 1937-1940s (Map case, Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes prints and news clippings depicting Japanese propaganda posters. See also: Box 143.
- Microfilm reels, 1869, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Reel 1, Lincoln C. Reynolds, Aviation in China, 1935 March 15
  - Reel 2, writings on China, 1869 April 10
    In English and Chinese.
- Flood in China, 1939 (Box 1)
- Johns Hopkins University, Operations Research Office, manuals, 1953 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- Far Eastern Commission, official English translation of new Japanese constitution, 1946 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Applications and personal history statements, 1949 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- European and Far Eastern personalities abstracts, Office of Strategic Services, Interdepartmental Committee for the Acquisition of Foreign Publications, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- Ethnographic Board, reports on area studies in American universities, volumes I-IV, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- American Institute of Pacific Relations, minutes from Executive Finance Committee meeting, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Correspondence regarding speech at National War College, 1957 (Box-folder 2: 7-8)
- Personal file, correspondence and clippings, 1941-1953 (Box 3)
- PhD diploma, 1935 (Box 4)
- Certificate of military service, 1949 (Box 4)
- American Political Science Association Committee on the Far East, correspondence, 1952 (Box 4)
- Georgetown University, 1957-1958 (Box 4)
- Personal correspondence, 1956 (Box 4)
- Political science course materials, 1939-1953 (Boxes 5-9)
- Japanese propaganda posters and flyers, 1930s (Box 10)
- Postcards depicting scenes from the Sino-Japanese War, late 1930s (Box 10)
- Bibliography, undated (Box 10)
- U.S. Air Force, correspondence, 1950-1951 (Box 10)
- U.S. Air Force, Human Resource Research Institute, correspondence, 1952 (Box 10)
- Copies of translated materials, 1954 (Box 11)
- Stanford project, correspondence (Box 11)
- Gradebook, 1946-1947 (Box 11)
- Agenda, minutes, and photograph from the meeting of the Institute of Public Relations, Pacific Council, Atlantic City, 1946 (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
- United Nations Conference on International Organization, San Francisco, 1945 April-May (Box-folder 12: 4-5)
- Correspondence, 1944-1954 (Box 13)
- Conference materials, 1946-1954 (Box 13)
- Conference materials, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 14: 1-4)
- A Manual for Writers of Dissertations, 1935 (Box-folder 14: 5)
- Function and Scope of the Human Relations Area, 1952 (Box-folder 14: 6)
- Visual education, 1939 (Box-folder 14: 7)
- Proposals for improvement in teaching international relations in smaller colleges and program of directed studies in liberal arts, circa 1946 (Box-folder 14: 8)
- Southeast Asian studies in American colleges and universities, 1952 (Box-folder 14: 9)
- Correspondence, 1945-1954, undated (Boxes 14-16)
  - Miscellaneous government agencies, 1951-1954 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - U.S. Department of State, Foreign Service Institute, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - U.S. Department of State, Far Eastern Division, Office of Information and Cultural Exchange, 1948 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1943-1951 (Box-folder 14: 13-15)
  - Navy Department, 1945 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - U.S. Senate, Committee on the Judiciary, McCarran Sub-Committee on Internal Security, 1952 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
  - Office of the Coordinator of Information, Far Eastern Section, method of indexing microfilm strips, undated (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Office of Strategic Services, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 15: 4-5)
    Includes project materials.
  - Office of War Information, 1945 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Indian Council of World Affairs, 1952 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Yuen-li Liang, 1947 (Box-folder 15: 8)
    Includes typescript of speech.
  - United Nations, Relief and Rehabilitation Administration, 1946 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs (Walter Rogers), 1947 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Philip Talbot, 1950 (Box-folder 15: 11)
  - A. Doak Barnett, 1948 (Box-folder 15: 12-15)
  - J.V. Williams, 1950 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- Institute of International Studies materials, 1943-1947 (Box-folder 16: 2-7)
- Speaking engagements, 1944-1951 (Box-folder 16: 8-10)
- Larchmont Forum for Public Opinion, correspondence, 1948 (Box-folder 16: 11)
- Speeches, writings, and lecture materials, 1946-1952 (Box-folder 16: 12-15)
- Correspondence with libraries, 1948-1950 (Box-folder 17: 1-6)
- United States Information Service American Library, Shanghai, 1948-1949 (Box-folder 17: 7)
- United States Information Service American Consulate General, Shanghai correspondence and pamphlets, circa 1937 (Box-folder 17: 8)
- Miscellaneous manuscripts, 1939-1947 (Box-folder 18: 1)
- Writings and collected writings, 1939-1952 (Boxes 18-19)
  - Esson M. Gale, "American Dilemma: East Asia or Western Europe?,", circa 1947 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - "Basic Factors in Political Reconstruction in China," Canadian Institute of International Affairs, 1946 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Man-shih Pen, "Can the Communists Industrialize China? Whither Should China Go?," for Voice of America, 1949 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - "China's Military Potential and the Enforcement of Peace,", 1943-1944 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Excerpts from the Economist Intelligence Unit, 1949 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - "The Far East and American Security,", undated (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Alexander Sachs, "Final Phase European War and Emerging Opportunity for Liquidating Far Eastern War,", 1945-1951 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Letters regarding the memorandum "China's Military Potential and the Enforcement of Peace,", 1943-1944 (Box-folder 18: 9)
  - "Collective Security in the Pacific,", 1945 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - W.A. Anderson, "Farmers Associations in Taiwan," report to the Joint Commission on Rural Reconstruction, 1950 December (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - "The Draft Constitution: Chapter VII of Senior Essay by Francis M. Ellis,", 1947 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - Yuan-li Wu, "An Interpretation of the Land Program of the Chinese Communist Party,", 1952 (Box-folder 18: 13)
  - Chiang Mon-lin, "The Land Reform in China,", 1950 December (Box-folder 18: 14)
  - "Outline of Chinese Culture,", undated (Box-folder 18: 15)
  - Listings of periodicals, undated (Box-folder 18: 16)
  - American China Policy Association newsletters and clippings, 1948 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - American Council of Learned Societies correspondence, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Zhou Fohai memoirs, 1943, English translation, 1945 November 8 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    Unpublished English translation.
  - "The Far Eastern Policy of the United States Since V-J Day," correspondence, 1947 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - D. N. Rowe, "The Postwar Treatment of Japan," outline for memorandum by D. N. Rowe, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - D. N. Rowe, "The Truth About Our China Policy,", 1949 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Outline of "The United States and the Soviet Empire" or "The Soviet Empire,", undated (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - Translation of an article appearing in the Wuhan Pao (J), Hankou, 1939 May 24 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - D. N. Rowe, "Where Can We Stand in Asia?," Yale University Foreign Studies, 1949 (Box-folder 19: 9)
- Correspondence, 1942-1954 (Boxes 19-21)
  - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals, 1953 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - American Oriental Society, Program Committee, 1948 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - American Political Science Association, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - China-American Council, 1944 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - China Institute in America, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Committee for Free Asia, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 19: 15)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1945 (Box-folder 19: 16)
  - Far Eastern Association, 1953 (Box-folder 19: 17)
  - Far Eastern Studies Organization, 1947 (Box-folder 19: 18)
  - Ford Foundation, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 19: 19)
  - The Board of Foreign Missions, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Harris Foundation, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Franklin Publications, 1953 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - American Committee in Aid of Chinese Industrial Cooperatives (Indusco), 1945-1946 (Box-folder 20: 4-5)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1942-1950 (Box-folder 20: 6-11)
    Includes minutes from meetings.
  - Radio Free Europe, Division of the National Committee for a Free Europe, 1953 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Henry Regnery Company Publishers, 1952-1954 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1949-1953 (Box-folder 21: 3)
    Includes draft of writings by Rowe.
- Social Science Research Council, writings, 1944 (Box-folder 21: 4)
- Correspondence, 1948-1953 (Box 21)
  - Stanford Research Institute, 1951 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    Includes expense claims.
  - Alfred Kohlberg, Inc., 1949-1953 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - League of Nations Association, 1943 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Time and Life, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - William Volker Charities Fund, 1953 (Box-folder 21: 9)
- Yale-in-China, 1946 (Box-folder 21: 10)
- Personnel files, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 21: 11-19)
- Project file, 1941-1953 (Boxes 21-22)
  - Collier's National Encyclopedia, Korea and Mongolia, 1952 (Box-folder 21: 20-21)
  - Collier's National Encyclopedia, Tibet, 1953 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - Collier's National Encyclopedia, 1953 (Box-folder 22: 2)
  - H. D. Lasswell, 1941 (Box-folder 22: 3)
    Includes memoranda and correspondence from United China Relief.
  - Orient Publishing Company (M.J. Stayner), 1953 (Box-folder 22: 4)
    Includes correspondence, magazines (The Orient), and monograph.
  - Research associates, 1948-1953 (Box-folder 22: 5-9)
    - Chih-tsing Hsia, 1953 (Box-folder 22: 5)
    - Paul M. Kattenburg, 1948 (Box-folder 22: 6)
    - C. S. Kwei, 1953 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - William R. Langdon, 1952 (Box-folder 22: 8)
    - I. Milton Sacks, 1953 (Box-folder 22: 9)
- Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 22: 10)
- Correspondence, 1954 (Box-folder 23: 1)
- Writings and collected writings, 1944-circa 1954 (Boxes 23-24)
  - "Far Eastern Policy of U.S. Since V-J Day,", circa 1947 (Box-folder 23: 2)
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1945-1952 (Box-folder 23: 3)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations data paper for American Council Conference, 1948 February (Box-folder 23: 4)
  - "A New Far Eastern Policy," article for Yale Review, 1950 (Box-folder 23: 5)
  - "American Policy Toward China," The ANNALS of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1947 (Box-folder 23: 6)
  - China Among the Powers, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 23: 7 - 24: 4)
    - Acknowledgements and comments, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 23: 7)
    - List of copies distributed, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - General correspondence, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - Manuscript, circa 1945 (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - Maps, circa 1945 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - Reviews, circa 1945 (Box-folder 24: 4)
  - The Contemporary National and Regions Series, McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1946-1948 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - T. Kase, "Journey to the Missouri," edited by D. N. Rowe, 1950 (Box-folder 24: 6)
  - "Foreign Affairs," American Quarterly Review, 1949 (Box-folder 24: 7)
  - "Readings on the Modern Far East," correspondence, 1950 (Box-folder 24: 8)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, correspondence, 1950 (Box-folder 24: 9)
  - John T. Flynn, "While You Slept," correspondence, 1952 (Box-folder 24: 10)
  - "The New Japanese Constitution," Far Eastern Survey, 1947 (Box-folder 24: 11)
  - Reviews, 1947-1954 (Box-folder 24: 12-13)
- Correspondence from radio broadcasts, 1945-1953 (Box-folder 24: 14)
- Radio scripts from "Yale Interprets the News,", 1950 (Box-folder 24: 15)
- Transcripts of radio broadcasts by Rowe, 1944-1953 (Box 25)
- Peace Committee, 1954 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- U.S. Army, Office of the Chief of Psychological Warfare, correspondence and travel documents, 1954 (Box-folder 26: 2)
- Paperwork from home rental in Connecticut, 1954 (Box-folder 26: 3)
- George Washington University, Human Resources Research Office, correspondence, 1954 (Box-folder 26: 4)
- Trips, 1944-1953 (Boxes 26-27)
  - Far Eastern region, 1954 (Box-folder 26: 5-11)
  - Atlantic City, 1946 (Box-folder 26: 12)
  - Canada, 1944 March 15-18 (Box-folder 26: 13)
    Canadian Institute of International Affairs discussion, "China in the Postwar World."
  - Chicago, 1945 (Box-folder 26: 14)
  - Far Eastern region, 1948 (Box-folder 26: 15-19)
  - Far Eastern region, 1948 (Box-folder 27: 1-3)
  - Japan, 1948 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - New York, 1944 (Box-folder 27: 5)
  - San Francisco, 1945 April-June (Box-folder 27: 6)
  - Santa Monica, 1948 May (Box-folder 27: 7)
  - Far Eastern region, 1948 (Box-folder 27: 8)
  - East Asia, 1948 (Box-folder 27: 9)
    Includes correspondence, map of Nanking, and pamphlets.
  - Washington D.C., 1947-1949 (Box-folder 27: 10-11)
  - Wilkes-Barre, 1947 March (Box-folder 27: 12)
- Army War College, 1953 (Box-folder 27: 13)
- S. C. Chen, correspondence, 1948 (Box-folder 27: 14)
- Miscellaneous printed matter, 1950-1954 (Box-folder 27: 15-16)
- Committee on International Relations, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 28: 1)
- Yale University, Department of Political Science, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 28: 2-4)
- Committee on Area and Language Study, 1948-1951 (Box-folder 28: 5)
- Department of International Relations, 1948 (Box-folder 28: 6)
- Yale University, Department of Political Science, 1952 (Box-folder 29: 1)
- Yale University, Department of Political Science, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 29: 2)
- Draft of proposal for research project on foreign area studies, 1952 March 25 (Box-folder 29: 3)
- Government department, 1949 (Box-folder 29: 4)
- Yale University Press, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 29: 5)
- Princeton Bicentennial Conference on the Far East, correspondence, speeches, and other materials, 1947 (Box-folder 29: 6-25)
- Princeton Bicentennial Conference on the Far East, correspondence, speeches, and other materials, 1947 (Box 30)
- Johns Hopkins University, Operations Research Office, project budget, circa 1950 (Box 30)
- Johns Hopkins University, Operations Research Office, project materials, 1950-1951 (Box 31)
- Johns Hopkins University, Operations Research Office, project materials, 1952 (Box 32)
- Johns Hopkins University, Operations Research Office, project materials, 1950s (Box 33)
- Photographs and negatives, 1955, undated (Box 34)
  Depictions of damaged buildings, forests and villages, military procession or parade, and Rowe at awards ceremonies and other engagements in Taiwan.
- Correspondence, 1955-1959 (Box 34)
- Asia Foundation, 1956-1958 (Box 34)
- Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 35)
- Bibliography of books on the Far East, undated (Box 35)
- Political science course materials, 1966 (Box 35)
- Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Box 36)
- United Nations, 1967-1968 (Box 36)
- Chinese Information Service, reports, 1968 (Box 36)
- Communism in China, printed matter, 1967-1968 (Box 36)
- Correspondence, 1954-1958 (Box 36)
- Political science course materials, 1953-1958 (Box 37)
- Thirteenth Report: Un-American Activities in California, 1965-1966 (Box 37)
- Course materials and lecture notes, 1957-1961 (Box 38)
- Final exams mailed to Rowe by graduate students, 1960 (Box 39)
- Political science course materials, 1933-1964 (Box 40)
- Political science course materials, 1964-1965 (Box 41)
- Briefing notes on U.S.-China policy, 1950s (Box 42)
- U.S. Army War College, 1960 (Box 42)
- Foreign policy, 1957-1960 (Box 42)
- Washington Report, newsletters, 1966-1967 (Box 43)
- Intelligence Digest, pamphlets, 1965-1967 (Box 43)
- Political science course materials, 1964-1966 (Box 43)
- Kiwanis Club and Rotary Club of Tokyo, 1965 (Box 44)
- Conference on the Far East, 1940 (Box 44)
- Correspondence, 1940 (Box 44)
- Marquette University, conference materials, 1959 (Box 45)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 45)
- Naval War College, 1959 (Box 45)
- Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 46)
- Correspondence and writings, 1959 (Box 47)
- Political science course materials, 1963-1964 (Box 47)
- Political science department materials, 1957-1958 (Box 47)
- Political science course materials, 1960-1961 (Box 48)
- Modern China, correspondence and reviews, 1960 (Box 48)
- United Nations investigation into Vietnam, 1961 (Box 49)
- Correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 49)
- Political science course materials, 1965 (Box 49)
- American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange, correspondence, memoranda, and meeting materials, 1959-1963 (Box 50)
- Institute of Political Psychology, correspondence and printed matter, 1957-1963 (Box 50)
- World Anti-Communist League (WACL), 1966-1967 (Box 50)
- Canadian National Defense College conference, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 51: 1)
- U.S. Senate, Committee on Foreign Relations, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 51: 2)
  Includes printed matter on communism in China.
- Friends of Free Asia, 1966 (Box-folder 51: 3)
- Trinity College history course materials, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 51: 4-5)
- Seminar for clergy, 1963 May (Box-folder 51: 6)
- Historical Research Foundation, 1963 (Box-folder 51: 7)
- China Institute in America, correspondence, minutes, and other materials, 1957-1966 (Box 52)
- American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange, correspondence, memoranda, and meeting materials, 1964-1965 (Box 52)
- General exams from political science course, 1966 (Box 52)
- RKO Broadcasting, correspondence, 1965 (Box 52)
- Conference materials, 1962-1965 (Boxes 53-54)
- Political science course materials, 1962-1963 (Box 54)
- Saigon conference photographs, 1963 (Box 55)
- Conference materials, 1961-1964 (Box 55)
- Clippings, 1964 (Box 55)
- Correspondence, 1961-1964 (Box 55)
- Conference materials, 1964 (Box 56)
- Issues and Studies: A Monthly Journal of World Affairs and Communist Problems, vols. 1-5, 1965-1969 (Box 56)